Guide to the Maurice Johnson, Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
[Papers]
1701-1800
OSBORN FC39
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.06
(1 volume)
MSS. Collection of notes, etc., from his papers.
Johnson, Maurice, 1688-1755
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn fc39. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
Antiquarians -- Great Britain; Drama -- Great Britain; Elegiac poetry, English; English poetry -- 18th century; Land tenure -- Law and legislation -- Great Britain; Legal manuscripts; Germany -- Kings and rulers; Great Britain -- Kings and rulers; Spalding (England); Bell, Beaupré, 1704-1745; Johnson, Maurice, 1688-1755; Ruggle, George, 1575-1622; Ruggle, George, 1575-1622 ( Ignoramus); Johnson family; Spalding Gentlemen's Society
- Osborn fc39
  - BELL, BEAUPRE, 1704-1741
    - ALS to [Maurice Johnson (1688-1775)], n.d. (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      n.p.
      1 p.; 23 x 17 cm.
      On an election and his vote.
      39/1
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - "Chronological Table of the Kings of Britain before Julius Caesars Arrival there 54 Years before the Coming of our Saviour Jesus Christ": anonymous MS, n.d. (Box 1)
      1 p.; 21 x 33 cm.
      Lists dates of kings of Britain
      also gives indications of other
      contemporary cultural events
      corresponds to a "time-line" of
      events.
      39/2
  - JOHNSON, JOHN
    - "Epitomy of the History of Germany and the House of Austria": autograph MS, 1742 (Box 1)
      15 p.; 16 x 10 cm.
      Contains dates, names of monarchs,
      and important events from 800 A.D.
      to 1711.
      39/3
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Miscellaneous Memoranda]: MSS (Box 1)
      32 items; various sizes
      Collection of items ranging from a
      penmanship sampler to MS copies of
      poetry both in Latin and in English.
      39/4
  - THURLOW, THOMAS, BP. OF DURHAM, 1737-1791
    - [Papers]: autograph MSS and anonymous MSS, 1782 Apr 6, n.d. (Box 1)
      4 items; various sizes
      DS dated 1782 Apr 6 to a copy of a
      letter to Maurice Johnson.
      39/5
  - [ANONYMOUS]
    - [Collection of verse]: autograph MSS, [18th c] (Box 1)
      7 items; various sizes
      Collection of MS copies of verse
      both in English and Latin.
      39/6